<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vox-Pol Conf Twitter Community</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/22/vox-pol-conf-twitter-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/22/vox-pol-conf-twitter-community/</guid>
      <description>This is a short notebook scraping tweets related to the Vox-Pol Conference 2018 in Amsterdam. As this was again a very inspiring Vox-Pol event I thought it was time to further explore the twitter community.
Packages Load the necessary packages
# install pacman once if not avaible on your machine # install.packages(&amp;quot;pacman&amp;quot;) pacman::p_load(tidyverse, purrr, tidyr, rtweet, stringr, ggraph, igraph, tidygraph, forcats)  Get Data Call Twitter API. If you want to scrape data yourself you have to register a free account where you get your personal access point to Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Preprocessing</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/01/text-preprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/01/text-preprocessing/</guid>
      <description>#install.packages(c(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pacman&amp;quot;)) #devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;rstudio/keras&amp;quot;) #devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;systats/tidyTX&amp;quot;) pacman::p_load( dplyr, stringr, manifestoR, purrr, tidyr, tidytext, tidyTX ) # keras::install_keras() Get data by manifestoR The manifestoR api is a nice project that offers the scientific community parties’ policy positions derived from a content analysis of parties’ electoral manifestos. Acquire your own free key after short registration. The project is present on github and provide a shiny app to explore their database
 mkey &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;__put__your__key__here__&amp;quot; mp_setapikey(key = mkey) # edate = Day, month, and year of national election df &amp;lt;- mp_corpus( countryname == &amp;quot;Germany&amp;quot; &amp;amp; edate &amp;gt; as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Classification in R</title>
      <link>/post/2018/03/07/text-classification-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/03/07/text-classification-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Today’s tutorial will cover how to perform text classification with keras (build on top of tensorflow). This is a fairly new but incredible experience for R users who have been limited in the past to more high level machine learning libraries like caret and h2o. These packages are great for a variety of machine learning tasks by the magic ensemble learning and hyperparameter grid search infrastructure from h2o. Despite some good feed forward networks, natural language or computer vision tasks require more complex network architectures to learn informative low dimensional features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Squared Simulations</title>
      <link>/post/2017/08/01/r-squared-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/08/01/r-squared-simulations/</guid>
      <description>The model performance measure \(R^2\) is often subject to fierce criticism for being prone to its context. This notebook describes some well known criticism of \(R^2\) and tests the deficiencies by simulations. By combining theory, code and accessible graphics I want to show the implications for getting any useful information from \(R^2\).
Literature The theoretical considerations are partly taken from
 The Elements of Statistical Learning p.14-16 Urban and Mayerl (2011) set up a poison list of 10 items to be considered, as \(R^2\) is artificially biased by other parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sentiment/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Neuron This is a demonstration of Sentiment Analysis which is a popular method in Natural Language Processing that measures the polarity of sentiments from text data. This app tells you whether it thinks the text you enter below expresses positive or negative sentiment.
--- 
  iframe { min-width: 100%; }    iFrameResize({ heightCalculationMethod: &#39;taggedElement&#39; });  Appendix The models for this app are trained on half of a million Amazon Book/Movie/App Reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic UI</title>
      <link>/semanticui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/semanticui/</guid>
      <description>code-mentor blogdown for websites dashboard examples https://www.nounou-top.fr/ learn semantic ui  Other Stuff Anyone know of an R package for interfacing with Alexa Skills? @thosjleeper @xieyihui @drob @JennyBryan @HoloMarkeD ?
&amp;mdash; Jeff Leek (@jtleek) April 12, 2017  XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Home  Messages  Friends    Learning Meant to be my personal learning sources.      Teaching The materials listed below are ...      ----     Learning  Teaching  Sources   First  Second  Third    ---</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>