<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Data Science on Simon&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Data Science on Simon&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Classification in R</title>
      <link>/post/2018/03/07/text-classification-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/03/07/text-classification-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Today’s tutorial will cover how to perform text classification with keras (build on top of tensorflow). This is a fairly new but incredible experience for R users who have been limited in the past to more high level machine learning libraries like caret and h2o. These packages are great for a variety of machine learning tasks by the magic ensemble learning and hyperparameter grid search infrastructure from h2o. Despite some good feed forward networks, natural language or computer vision tasks require more complex network architectures to learn informative low dimensional features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown, Highcharter and R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018/03/05/blogdown-highcharter-and-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/03/05/blogdown-highcharter-and-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>First Header library(&amp;quot;highcharter&amp;quot;) ## Highcharts (www.highcharts.com) is a Highsoft software product which is ## not free for commercial and Governmental use data(diamonds, mpg, package = &amp;quot;ggplot2&amp;quot;) hchart(mpg, &amp;quot;scatter&amp;quot;, hcaes(x = displ, y = hwy, group = class))  {&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic UI</title>
      <link>/semanticui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/semanticui/</guid>
      <description>code-mentor blogdown for websites dashboard examples https://www.nounou-top.fr/ learn semantic ui  Other Stuff Anyone know of an R package for interfacing with Alexa Skills? @thosjleeper @xieyihui @drob @JennyBryan @HoloMarkeD ?
&amp;mdash; Jeff Leek (@jtleek) April 12, 2017  XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Learning Meant to be my personal learning sources.      Teaching The materials listed below are ...      ----    --- Learning  Teaching  Sources   First  Second  Third</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>